This info is taken from Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia.

The most popular programming languages are: C, Java, PHP, JavaScript, C++, Python, Shell, Ruby, Objective-C and C#.


1.C (programming language)

In computing, C  is a general-purpose programming language initially developed by Dennis Ritchie between 1969 and 1973 at AT&T Bell Labs.
Like most imperative languages in the ALGOL tradition, C has facilities for structured programming and allows lexical variable scope and recursion,while a static type system prevents many unintended operations.
Its design provides constructs that map efficiently to typical machine instructions, and therefore it has found lasting use in applications that had formerly been coded in assembly language,most notably system software like the Unix computer operating system.

C is one of the most widely used programming languages of all time, and C compilers are available for the majority of available computer architectures and operating systems.

Many later languages have borrowed directly or indirectly from C, including D, Go, Rust, Java, JavaScript, Limbo, LPC, C#, Objective-C, Perl, PHP, Python, Verilog (hardware description language),and Unix's C shell. These languages have drawn many of their control structures and other basic features from C. 
Most of them (with Python being the most dramatic exception) are also very syntactically similar to C in general, and they tend to combine the recognizable expression and statement syntax of C with underlying type systems,data models, and semantics that can be radically different. C++ and Objective-C started as compilers that generated C code; C++ is currently nearly a superset of C, while Objective-C is a strict superset of C.



2.Java (programming language)

Java is a computer programming language that is concurrent, class-based, object-oriented, and specifically designed to have as few implementation dependencies as possible.
It is intended to let application developers "write once, run anywhere" (WORA), meaning that code that runs on one platform does not need to be recompiled to run on another.
Java applications are typically compiled to bytecode (class file) that can run on any Java virtual machine (JVM) regardless of computer architecture. 
Java is, as of 2014, one of the most popular programming languages in use, particularly for client-server web applications, with a reported 9 million developers.
Java was originally developed by James Gosling at Sun Microsystems (which has since merged into Oracle Corporation) and released in 1995 as a core component of Sun Microsystems' Java platform.
The language derives much of its syntax from C and C++, but it has fewer low-level facilities than either of them.

The original and reference implementation Java compilers, virtual machines, and class libraries were developed by Sun from 1991 and first released in 1995. As of May 2007,in compliance with the specifications of the Java Community Process, Sun relicensed most of its Java technologies under the GNU General Public License.
Others have also developed alternative implementations of these Sun technologies, such as the GNU Compiler for Java (bytecode compiler), GNU Classpath (standard libraries),and IcedTea-Web (browser plugin for applets).

There were five primary goals in the creation of the Java language:
1.It should be "simple, object-oriented and familiar"
2.It should be "robust and secure"
3.It should be "architecture-neutral and portable"
4.It should execute with "high performance"
5.It should be "interpreted, threaded, and dynamic"



3.PHP (programming language)



PHP is a server-side scripting language designed for web development but also used as a general-purpose programming language. 
PHP is now installed on more than 244 million websites and 2.1 million web servers. Originally created by Rasmus Lerdorf in 1995,the reference implementation of PHP is now produced by The PHP Group.
While PHP originally stood for Personal Home Page,it now stands for PHP: Hypertext Preprocessor, a recursive backronym.

PHP code is interpreted by a web server with a PHP processor module, which generates the resulting web page: PHP commands can be embedded directly into an HTML
source document rather than calling an external file to process data.
It has also evolved to include a command-line interface capability and can be used in standalone graphical applications

PHP is free software released under the PHP License. PHP can be deployed on most web servers and also as a standalone shell on almost every operating system and platform,free of charge.





4.JavaScript (programming language)

JavaScript (JS) is a dynamic computer programming language. It is most commonly used as part of web browsers, whose implementations allow client-side scripts to interact with the user,control the browser, communicate asynchronously, and alter the document content that is displayed. It is also being used in server-side programming, game development and the creation of desktop and mobile applications.

JavaScript is a prototype-based scripting language with dynamic typing and has first-class functions. Its syntax was influenced by C. JavaScript copies many names and naming conventions from Java,but the two languages are otherwise unrelated and have very different semantics. The key design principles within JavaScript are taken from the Self and Scheme programming languages.
It is a multi-paradigm language, supporting object-oriented, imperative, and functional programming styles.

The application of JavaScript to use outside of web pages—for example, in PDF documents, site-specific browsers, and desktop widgets—is also significant.
Newer and faster JavaScript VMs and platforms built upon them (notably Node.js) have also increased the popularity of JavaScript for server-side web applications.
On the client side, JavaScript was traditionally implemented as an interpreted language but just-in-time compilation is now performed by recent (post-2012) browsers.

JavaScript was formalized in the ECMAScript language standard and is primarily used as part of a web browser (client-side JavaScript). 
This enables programmatic access to computational objects within a host environment.





5.C++ (programming language)

C++ (pronounced see plus plus) is a general purpose programming language that is free-form and compiled. It is regarded as an intermediate-level language,as it comprises both high-level and low-level language features.It provides imperative, object-oriented and generic programming features.

C++ is one of the most popular programming languages and is implemented on a wide variety of hardware and operating system platforms. 
As an efficient performance driven programming language it is used in systems software, application software, device drivers, embedded software, high-performance server and client applications,and entertainment software such as video games.Various entities provide both open source and proprietary C++ compiler software, including the FSF, LLVM, Microsoft and Intel.
C++ has influenced many other programming languages, for example, C# and Java.

It was developed by Bjarne Stroustrup starting in 1979 at Bell Labs, C++ was originally named C with Classes, adding object-oriented features, such as classes,and other enhancements to the C programming language. The language was renamed C++ in 1983, as a pun involving the increment operator. It began as enhancements to C,first adding classes, then virtual functions, operator overloading, multiple inheritance, templates and exception handling, alongside changes to the type system and other features.



6.C# (programming language)


C♯ (pronounced see sharp) is a multi-paradigm programming language encompassing strong typing, imperative, declarative, functional, procedural, generic,object-oriented (class-based), and component-oriented programming disciplines. It was developed by Microsoft within its .NET initiative and later approved as a standard by Ecma (ECMA-334) 
and ISO (ISO/IEC 23270:2006). C♯ is one of the programming languages designed for the Common Language Infrastructure. C# is built on the syntax and semantics of C++,allowing C programmers to take advantage of .NET and the common language runtime.


The ECMA standard lists these design goals for C#:
-The C# language is intended to be a simple, modern, general-purpose, object-oriented programming language.
-The language, and implementations thereof, should provide support for software engineering principles such as strong type checking, array bounds checking, detection of attempts to use uninitialized variables, and automatic garbage collection. Software robustness, durability, and programmer productivity are important.
-The language is intended for use in developing software components suitable for deployment in distributed environments.
-Source code portability is very important, as is programmer portability, especially for those programmers already familiar with C and C++.
-Support for internationalization is very important.
-C# is intended to be suitable for writing applications for both hosted and embedded systems, ranging from the very large that use sophisticated operating systems, down to the very small having dedicated functions.
-Although C# applications are intended to be economical with regard to memory and processing power requirements, the language was not intended to compete directly on performance and size with C or assembly language.





