What exactly is compilation?
In a compiled implementation of a language, a compiler will translate the program directly into code that is specific to the target machine, which is also known as machine code – basically code that is specific to a given processor and operating system. Then the computer will run the machine code on its own.
Examples: C, C++, C#, Java


What exactly is interpretation?
In an interpreted implementation of a language, the source code is not directly run by the target machine. What happens instead is that another program reads and then executes the original source code. This other program is also known as the interpreter. The interpreter is usually written specifically for the native machine. As an example, you could consider the multiplier operation – the “*”. If the interpreter sees this in your code, then at run time it would call its own definition of the multiplier function – maybe something called “multiply(x,y)”. And then that “multiply(x,y)” would execute the machine code’s equivalent of the multiply instruction.

In interpretation, the original source code is also typically converted into some intermediate code which is then processed by an interpreter that converts the intermediate code into machine specific code.
Exapmles: JavaScript, PHP, Perl