This info is taken from Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia.

Integrated development environments

For C and C++:

 Anjuta, Code::Blocks, CodeLite, Dev-C++, Eclipse, GNAT Programming Studio, KDevelop, Kuzya, MonoDevelop, NetBeans, QDevelop, Qt Creator, 
 wxDev-C++, Ultimate++, Pelles C, Sun Studio, Xcode, C++Builder, CodeWarrior, IBM VisualAge, Visual Studio(Express) 

For Java 

 Android Studio, BlueJ, Eclipse, JetBrains IntelliJ IDEA, Greenfoot, KDevelop, JBuilder, JCreator, JDeveloper, jGRASP, MyEclipse, 
 NetBeans, IBM Rational Application Developer for WebSphere
 

For .NET

 Compilr, MonoDevelop, SharpDevelop, Visual Studio (Express) 


1. Code::Blocks

Code::Blocks is a free and open source, cross-platform IDE which supports multiple compilers including GCC and Visual C++.
It is developed in C++ using wxWidgets as the GUI toolkit. Using a plugin architecture, its capabilities and features are defined by the provided plugins.
Currently, Code::Blocks is oriented towards C, C++, and Fortran. It can also be used for creating ARM, AVR, D, DirectX, FLTK,
GLFW, GLUT, GTK+, Irrlicht, Lightfeather, MATLAB, OGRE, OpenGL, Qt, SDL, SFML, STL, SmartWin and wx programs and applications, 
although in some cases installing third-party SDKs or frameworks is necessary.

Code::Blocks is being developed for Windows, Linux, and Mac OS X and has been ported to FreeBSD, OpenBSD, and Solaris.

The latest stable version as of December 2013 is Code::Blocks 13.12, was released on December 27, 2013.



2. Eclipse


 Eclipse is an integrated development environment (IDE). It contains a base workspace and an extensible plug-in system for customizing the environment.
 Written mostly in Java, Eclipse can be used to develop applications. By means of various plug-ins, Eclipse may also be used to develop applications in other programming languages:
 Ada, C, C++, COBOL, Fortran, Haskell, JavaScript, Lasso, Perl, PHP, Python, R, Ruby (including Ruby on Rails framework), Scala, Clojure, Groovy,
 Scheme, and Erlang. It can also be used to develop packages for the software Mathematica. Development environments include the Eclipse Java development tools (JDT) for Java and Scala,
 Eclipse CDT for C/C++ and Eclipse PDT for PHP, among others.

The initial codebase originated from IBM VisualAge.The Eclipse software development kit (SDK),
which includes the Java development tools, is meant for Java developers. Users can extend its abilities by installing plug-ins written for the Eclipse Platform,
such as development toolkits for other programming languages, and can write and contribute their own plug-in modules.

Released under the terms of the Eclipse Public License, Eclipse SDK is free and open source software (although it is incompatible with the GNU General Public License).
It was one of the first IDEs to run under GNU Classpath and it runs without problems under IcedTea.




3. Android Studio


Android Studio is an integrated development environment (IDE) for the Android platform. It was announced on 16 May 2013 by Google's Product Manager, Ellie Powers,
at that year's Google I/O conference. As of June 2013, it is available for users to try (for free) as an early access preview. 
Based on JetBrains' IntelliJ IDEA software, the Studio is designed specifically for Android development.
It is available for download on Windows, Mac OS X and Linux.


Several features are expected to be rolled out to the users as the software matures; currently, however the following features are provided for:
-Live Layout: WYSIWYG Editor - Live Coding - Real-time App Rendering.
-Developer Console: optimization tips, assistance for translation, referral tracking, campaigning and promotions - Usage Metrics.
-Provision for beta releases and staged rollout.
-Gradle-based build support.
-Android-specific refactoring and quick fixes.
-Lint tools to catch performance, usability, version compatibility and other problems.
-ProGuard and app-signing capabilities.
-Template-based wizards to create common Android designs and components.
-A rich layout editor that allows you to drag-and-drop UI components, option to preview layouts on multiple screen configurations.







4. MonoDevelop


MonoDevelop is an open source integrated development environment for Linux, OS X,and Windows.
Its primary focus is development of projects that use Mono and .NET frameworks.
MonoDevelop integrates features similar to those of NetBeans and Microsoft Visual Studio, such as automatic code completion, source control,
a graphical user interface (GUI) and Web designer. MonoDevelop integrates a Gtk# GUI designer called Stetic.It supports C#, F#, Java,
Boo, Visual Basic.NET, Oxygene, CIL, Python, Vala, C and C++.





5. Visual Studio


Microsoft Visual Studio is an integrated development environment (IDE) from Microsoft. It is used to develop console and graphical user 
interface applications along with Windows Forms or WPF applications, web sites, web applications, web services, and also Windows Store apps in both native code together
with managed code for all platforms supported by Microsoft Windows, Windows Mobile, Windows CE, .NET Framework, .NET Compact Framework and Microsoft Silverlight.

Visual Studio includes a code editor supporting IntelliSense as well as code refactoring. The integrated debugger works both as 
a source-level debugger and a machine-level debugger. Other built-in tools include a forms designer for building GUI applications,
web designer, class designer, and database schema designer. It accepts plug-ins that enhance the functionality at almost every level—including adding support for source-control systems
(like Subversion and Visual SourceSafe) and adding new toolsets like editors and visual designers for domain-specific languages or toolsets for other aspects of the software development lifecycle
(like the Team Foundation Server client: Team Explorer).

Visual Studio supports different programming languages by means of language services, which allow the code editor and debugger to support
to varying degrees) nearly any programming language, provided a language-specific service exists. Built-in languages include C/C++ (via Visual C++),
 VB.NET (via Visual Basic .NET), C# (via Visual C#), and F# (as of Visual Studio 2010). Support for other languages such as M, Python, and Ruby among others 
is available via language services installed separately. It also supports XML/XSLT, HTML/XHTML, JavaScript and CSS. Individual language-specific versions 
of Visual Studio also exist which provide more limited language services to the user: Microsoft Visual Basic, Visual J#, Visual C#, and Visual C++.

Microsoft provides "Express" editions of its Visual Studio at no cost. Commercial versions of Visual Studio along with select past versions are available
for free to students via Microsoft's DreamSpark program.











